 <chapter id="fields-and-charsets">
  <title>Field Structure and Character Sets
  </title>
  
  <para>
   In order to provide a flexible approach to national character set
   handling, &zebra; allows the administrator to configure the set up the
   system to handle any 8-bit character set &mdash; including sets that
   require multi-octet diacritics or other multi-octet characters. The
   definition of a character set includes a specification of the
   permissible values, their sort order (this affects the display in the
   SCAN function), and relationships between upper- and lowercase
   characters. Finally, the definition includes the specification of
   space characters for the set.
  </para>

  <para>
   The operator can define different character sets for different fields,
   typical examples being standard text fields, numerical fields, and
   special-purpose fields such as WWW-style linkages (URx).
  </para>

  <para>
   Zebra 1.3 and Zebra versions 2.0.18 and earlier required that the field
   type is a single character, e.g. <literal>w</literal> (for word), and
   <literal>p</literal> for phrase. Zebra 2.0.20 and later allow field types 
   to be any string. This allows for greater flexibility - in particular
   per-locale (language) fields can be defined.
  </para>

  <para>
   Version 2.1 of Zebra can also be configured - per field - to use the
   <ulink url="&url.icu;">ICU</ulink> library to perform tokenization and
   normalization of strings. This is an alternative to the "charmap"
   files which has been part of Zebra since its first release.
  </para>

  <section id="default-idx-file">
   <title>The default.idx file</title>
   <para>
    The field types, and hence character sets, are associated with data
    elements by the indexing rules (say <literal>title:w</literal>) in the
    various filters. Fields are defined in a field definition file which,
    by default, is called <filename>default.idx</filename>. 
    This file provides the association between field type codes 
    and the character map files (with the .chr suffix). The format
    of the .idx file is as follows
   </para>
   
   <para>
    <variablelist>

     <varlistentry>
      <term>index <replaceable>field type code</replaceable></term>
      <listitem>
       <para>
	This directive introduces a new search index code.
	The argument is a one-character code to be used in the
	.abs files to select this particular index type. An index, roughly,
	corresponds to a particular structure attribute during search. Refer
	to <xref linkend="zebrasrv-search"/>.
       </para>
      </listitem></varlistentry>
     <varlistentry>
      <term>sort <replaceable>field code type</replaceable></term>
      <listitem>
       <para>
	This directive introduces a 
	sort index. The argument is a one-character code to be used in the
	.abs fie to select this particular index type. The corresponding
	use attribute must be used in the sort request to refer to this
	particular sort index. The corresponding character map (see below)
	is used in the sort process.
       </para>
      </listitem></varlistentry>
     <varlistentry>
      <term>completeness <replaceable>boolean</replaceable></term>
      <listitem>
       <para>
	This directive enables or disables complete field indexing.
	The value of the <replaceable>boolean</replaceable> should be 0
	(disable) or 1. If completeness is enabled, the index entry will
	contain the complete contents of the field (up to a limit), with words
	(non-space characters) separated by single space characters
	(normalized to " " on display). When completeness is
	disabled, each word is indexed as a separate entry. Complete subfield
	indexing is most useful for fields which are typically browsed (e.g.,
	titles, authors, or subjects), or instances where a match on a
	complete subfield is essential (e.g., exact title searching). For fields
	where completeness is disabled, the search engine will interpret a
	search containing space characters as a word proximity search.
       </para>
      </listitem></varlistentry>

     <varlistentry id="default.idx.firstinfield">
      <term>firstinfield <replaceable>boolean</replaceable></term>
      <listitem>
       <para>
	This directive enables or disables first-in-field indexing.
	The value of the <replaceable>boolean</replaceable> should be 0
	(disable) or 1. 
       </para>
      </listitem></varlistentry>

     <varlistentry id="default.idx.alwaysmatches">
      <term>alwaysmatches <replaceable>boolean</replaceable></term>
      <listitem>
       <para>
	This directive enables or disables alwaysmatches indexing.
	The value of the <replaceable>boolean</replaceable> should be 0
	(disable) or 1. 
       </para>
      </listitem></varlistentry>

     <varlistentry>
      <term>charmap <replaceable>filename</replaceable></term>
      <listitem>
       <para>
	This is the filename of the character
	map to be used for this index for field type.
        See <xref linkend="character-map-files"/> for details.
       </para>
      </listitem></varlistentry>
     
     <varlistentry>
      <term>icuchain <replaceable>filename</replaceable></term>
      <listitem>
       <para>
	Specifies the filename with ICU tokenization and
	normalization rules. 
	See <xref linkend="icuchain-files"/> for details.
	Using icuchain for a field type is an alternative to
	charmap. It does not make sense to define both
	icuchain and charmap for the same field type.
       </para>
      </listitem></varlistentry>
    </variablelist>
   </para>
   <example id="field-types">
    <title>Field types</title>
    <para>
     Following are three excerpts of the standard
     <filename>tab/default.idx</filename> configuration file. Notice
     that the <literal>index</literal> and <literal>sort</literal>
     are grouping directives, which bind all other following directives
     to them:
     <screen>
     # Traditional word index
     # Used if completeness is 'incomplete field' (@attr 6=1) and
     # structure is word/phrase/word-list/free-form-text/document-text
     index w
     completeness 0
     position 1
     alwaysmatches 1
     firstinfield 1
     charmap string.chr

     ...

     # Null map index (no mapping at all)
     # Used if structure=key (@attr 4=3)
     index 0
     completeness 0
     position 1
     charmap @

     ...

     # Sort register
     sort s
     completeness 1
     charmap string.chr
     </screen>
    </para>
   </example>
  </section>

  <section id="character-map-files">
   <title>Charmap Files</title>
   <para>
    The character map files are used to define the word tokenization
    and character normalization performed before inserting text into
    the inverse indexes. &zebra; ships with the predefined character map
    files <filename>tab/*.chr</filename>. Users are allowed to add
    and/or modify maps according to their needs.  
   </para>

   <table id="character-map-table" frame="top">
     <title>Character maps predefined in &zebra;</title>
      <tgroup cols="3">
       <thead>
        <row>
         <entry>File name</entry>
         <entry>Intended type</entry>
         <entry>Description</entry>
        </row>
       </thead>
       <tbody>
        <row>
         <entry><literal>numeric.chr</literal></entry>
         <entry><literal>:n</literal></entry>
         <entry>Numeric digit tokenization and normalization map. All
         characters not in the set <literal>-{0-9}.,</literal> will be
         suppressed. Note that floating point numbers are processed
         fine, but scientific exponential numbers are trashed.</entry>
        </row>
        <row>
         <entry><literal>scan.chr</literal></entry>
         <entry><literal>:w or :p</literal></entry>
         <entry>Word tokenization char map for Scandinavian
         languages. This one resembles the generic word tokenization
         character map <literal>tab/string.chr</literal>, the main
         differences are sorting of the special characters 
        <literal>üzæäøöå</literal> and equivalence maps according to
         Scandinavian language rules.</entry>
        </row>
        <row>
         <entry><literal>string.chr</literal></entry>
         <entry><literal>:w or :p</literal></entry>
         <entry>General word tokenization and normalization character
         map, mostly useful for English texts. Use this to derive your
         own language tokenization and normalization derivatives.</entry>
        </row>
        <row>
         <entry><literal>urx.chr</literal></entry>
         <entry><literal>:u</literal></entry>
         <entry>URL parsing and tokenization character map.</entry>
        </row>
        <row>
         <entry><literal>@</literal></entry>
         <entry><literal>:0</literal></entry>
         <entry>Do-nothing character map used for literal binary
         indexing. There is no existing file associated to it, and
         there is no normalization or tokenization performed at all.</entry>
        </row>
      </tbody>
     </tgroup>
   </table>

   <para>
    The contents of the character map files are structured as follows:
    <variablelist>
     <varlistentry>
      <term>encoding <replaceable>encoding-name</replaceable></term>
      <listitem>
       <para>
	This directive must be at the very beginning of the file, and it
        specifies the character encoding used in the entire file. If
        omitted, the encoding <literal>ISO-8859-1</literal> is assumed.
       </para>
       <para>
        For example, one of the test files found at  
          <literal>test/rusmarc/tab/string.chr</literal> contains the following
        encoding directive:
        <screen>
         encoding koi8-r
        </screen>
          and the test file
          <literal>test/charmap/string.utf8.chr</literal> is encoded
          in UTF-8:
        <screen>
         encoding utf-8
        </screen>
       </para>
      </listitem></varlistentry>

     <varlistentry>
      <term>lowercase <replaceable>value-set</replaceable></term>
      <listitem>
       <para>
	This directive introduces the basic value set of the field type.
	The format is an ordered list (without spaces) of the
	characters which may occur in "words" of the given type.
	The order of the entries in the list determines the
	sort order of the index. In addition to single characters, the
	following combinations are legal:
       </para>

       <para>

	<itemizedlist>
	 <listitem>
	  <para>
	   Backslashes may be used to introduce three-digit octal, or
	   two-digit hex representations of single characters
	   (preceded by <literal>x</literal>).
	   In addition, the combinations
	   \\, \\r, \\n, \\t, \\s (space &mdash; remember that real
	   space-characters may not occur in the value definition), and
	   \\ are recognized, with their usual interpretation.
	  </para>
	 </listitem>

	 <listitem>
	  <para>
	   Curly braces {} may be used to enclose ranges of single
	   characters (possibly using the escape convention described in the
	   preceding point), e.g., {a-z} to introduce the
	   standard range of ASCII characters.
	   Note that the interpretation of such a range depends on
	   the concrete representation in your local, physical character set.
	  </para>
	 </listitem>

	 <listitem>
	  <para>
	   parentheses () may be used to enclose multi-byte characters -
	   e.g., diacritics or special national combinations (e.g., Spanish
	   "ll"). When found in the input stream (or a search term),
	   these characters are viewed and sorted as a single character, with a
	   sorting value depending on the position of the group in the value
	   statement.
	  </para>
	 </listitem>

	</itemizedlist>

       </para>
       <para>
        For example, <literal>scan.chr</literal> contains the following
        lowercase normalization and sorting order:
        <screen>
         lowercase {0-9}{a-y}üzæäøöå
        </screen>
       </para>
      </listitem></varlistentry>
     <varlistentry>
      <term>uppercase <replaceable>value-set</replaceable></term>
      <listitem>
       <para>
	This directive introduces the
	upper-case equivalences to the value set (if any). The number and
	order of the entries in the list should be the same as in the
	<literal>lowercase</literal> directive.
       </para>
       <para>
        For example, <literal>scan.chr</literal> contains the following
        uppercase equivalent:
        <screen>
         uppercase {0-9}{A-Y}ÜZÆÄØÖÅ
        </screen>
       </para>
      </listitem></varlistentry>
     <varlistentry>
      <term>space <replaceable>value-set</replaceable></term>
      <listitem>
       <para>
	This directive introduces the character
	which separate words in the input stream. Depending on the
	completeness mode of the field in question, these characters either
	terminate an index entry, or delimit individual "words" in
	the input stream. The order of the elements is not significant &mdash;
	otherwise the representation is the same as for the
	<literal>uppercase</literal> and <literal>lowercase</literal>
	directives.
       </para>
       <para>
        For example, <literal>scan.chr</literal> contains the following
        space instruction:
        <screen><![CDATA[
         space {\001-\040}!"#$%&'\()*+,-./:;<=>?@\[\\]^_`\{|}~
        ]]></screen>
       </para>
      </listitem></varlistentry>
     <varlistentry>
      <term>map <replaceable>value-set</replaceable>
       <replaceable>target</replaceable></term>
      <listitem>
       <para>
	This directive introduces a mapping between each of the
	members of the value-set on the left to the character on the
	right. The character on the right must occur in the value
	set (the <literal>lowercase</literal> directive) of the
	character set, but it may be a parenthesis-enclosed
	multi-octet character. This directive may be used to map
	diacritics to their base characters, or to map HTML-style
	character-representations to their natural form, etc. The
	map directive can also be used to ignore leading articles in
	searching and/or sorting, and to perform other special
	transformations.
       </para>
       <para>
        For example, <literal>scan.chr</literal> contains the following
        map instructions among others, to make sure that HTML entity
        encoded  Danish special characters are mapped to the
        equivalent Latin-1 characters:
        <screen><![CDATA[
         map (&aelig;)      æ
         map (&oslash;)     ø
         map (&aring;)      å
        ]]></screen>
	</para>
       <para>
	In addition to specifying sort orders, space (blank) handling,
	and upper/lowercase folding, you can also use the character map
	files to make &zebra; ignore leading articles in sorting records,
	or when doing complete field searching.
       </para>
       <para>
	This is done using the <literal>map</literal> directive in the
	character map file. In a nutshell, what you do is map certain
	sequences of characters, when they occur <emphasis> in the
	 beginning of a field</emphasis>, to a space. Assuming that the
	character "@" is defined as a space character in your file, you
	can do:
	<screen>
	 map (^The\s) @
	 map (^the\s) @
	</screen>
	The effect of these directives is to map either 'the' or 'The',
	followed by a space character, to a space. The hat ^ character
	denotes beginning-of-field only when complete-subfield indexing
	or sort indexing is taking place; otherwise, it is treated just
	as any other character.
       </para>
       <para>
	Because the <literal>default.idx</literal> file can be used to
	associate different character maps with different indexing types
	-- and you can create additional indexing types, should the need
	arise -- it is possible to specify that leading articles should
	be ignored either in sorting, in complete-field searching, or
	both.
       </para>
       <para>
	If you ignore certain prefixes in sorting, then these will be
	eliminated from the index, and sorting will take place as if
	they weren't there. However, if you set the system up to ignore
	certain prefixes in <emphasis>searching</emphasis>, then these
	are deleted both from the indexes and from query terms, when the
	client specifies complete-field searching. This has the effect
	that a search for 'the science journal' and 'science journal'
	would both produce the same results.
       </para>
      </listitem></varlistentry>
     <varlistentry>
      <term>equivalent <replaceable>value-set</replaceable></term>
      <listitem>
       <para>
	This directive introduces equivalence classes of characters
	and/or strings for sorting purposes only. It resembles the map
	directive, but does not affect search and retrieval indexing,
	but only sorting order under present requests. 
       </para>
       <para>
        For example, <literal>scan.chr</literal> contains the following
        equivalent sorting instructions, which can be uncommented:
        <screen><![CDATA[
         # equivalent æä(ae)
         # equivalent øö(oe)
         # equivalent å(aa)
         # equivalent uü
        ]]></screen>
       </para>
      </listitem></varlistentry>
    </variablelist>
   </para>
  </section>

  <section id="icuchain-files">
   <title>ICU Chain Files</title>
   <para>
    The <ulink url="&url.icu;">ICU</ulink> chain files defines a 
    <emphasis>chain</emphasis> of rules
    which specify the conversion process to be carried out for each
    record string for indexing.
   </para>
   <para>
    Both searching and sorting is based on the <emphasis>sort</emphasis>
    normalization that ICU provides. This means that scan and sort will
    return terms in the sort order given by ICU.
   </para>
   <para>
    Zebra is using YAZ' ICU wrapper. Refer to the 
    <ulink url="&url.yaz.yaz-icu;">yaz-icu man page</ulink> for
    documentation about the ICU chain rules.
   </para>
   <tip>
    <para>
     Use the yaz-icu program to test your icuchain rules.
    </para>
   </tip>
   <example id="indexing-greek-example"><title>Indexing Greek text</title>
    <para>
     Consider a system where all "regular" text is to be indexed
     using as Greek (locale: EL).
     We would have to change our index type file - to read
     <screen>
      # Index greek words
      index w
      completeness 0
      position 1
      alwaysmatches 1
      firstinfield 1
      icuahain greek.xml
      ..
     </screen>
     The ICU chain file <filename>greek.xml</filename> could look
     as follows:
     <screen><![CDATA[
      <icu_chain locale="el">
      <transform rule="[:Control:] Any-Remove"/>
      <tokenize rule="l"/>
      <transform rule="[[:WhiteSpace:][:Punctuation:]] Remove"/>
      <display/>
      <casemap rule="l"/>
     </icu_chain>
     ]]></screen>
    </para>
   </example>
   <para>
    Zebra is shipped with a field types file <filename>icu.idx</filename>
    which is an ICU chain version of <filename>default.idx</filename>.
   </para>

   <example id="indexing-marcxml-example"><title>MARCXML indexing using ICU</title>
    <para>
     The directory <filename>examples/marcxml</filename> includes
     a complete sample with MARCXML records that are DOM XML indexed 
     using ICU chain rules. Study the
     <filename>README</filename> in the <filename>marcxml</filename>
     directory for details.
    </para>
   </example>
  </section>

 </chapter>
 <!-- Keep this comment at the end of the file
 Local variables:
 mode: sgml
 sgml-omittag:t
 sgml-shorttag:t
 sgml-minimize-attributes:nil
 sgml-always-quote-attributes:t
 sgml-indent-step:1
 sgml-indent-data:t
 sgml-parent-document: "zebra.xml"
 sgml-local-catalogs: nil
 sgml-namecase-general:t
 End:
 -->
